DMITRY KALINCHENKO

Boulder, CO | 734.834.1395 | dmitry.kalinchenko@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/dkalinchenko

SUMMARY

Management consultant and project manager with experience working for Fortune 100 companies in a diverse set of industries. Graduate degree from top-tier university. Experience with agile software development as both a developer and PM. Strong project management, market research, verbal and written communication and relationship building skills.

KEY SKILLS

Scrum/Project Management: 3 years of experience guiding projects from inception through completion in management consulting as well as Agile Scrum environment. 6 years of experience of building relationships with senior leadership, presenting cases, and conducting brainstorming sessions with senior executives of large organizations.

Primary Research & Voice of the Customer: 5 years of experience identifying, recruiting, interviewing and synthesizing insights from dozens of individuals for a variety of projects in a range of industries from consumer goods to basic chemicals.

Visual Design: 10+ years of experience designing visually compelling and complex charts, presentations, user interfaces, and marketing materials. Proficient with Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign and Balasmiq.

Market Research & Sizing: 5 years of experience doing market research, forecasting and sizing studies in service of setting the market context for new opportunities. Developed Excel-based models to project growth and estimate the future markets.

Web Design & Development: Proficient with HTML/CSS. Intermediate SQL and JavaScript skillset including jQuery and D3.js

EXPERIENCE

Consultant (March 2016 – Present) | Analyst (March 2014 – March 2016)

The Inovo Group | Boulder, CO

Inovo is an innovation consulting firm specializing in working with clients in energy, chemical and material industries. As a consultant I manage initial pilots to mid-sized projects, perform market analysis and primary and secondary research in support of discovering of new strategic opportunities for our clients. Some notable accomplishments:

- Developed a framework for quick and effective market sizing studies
- Redesigned the structure of the Inovo's opportunity templates one of the centerpieces of Inovo's framework
- Redesigned the look and feel of the standard templates to make them more visually impactful and user-friendly

During my time with Inovo, I worked with companies like: ExxonMobil, Nestle Purina, Dow Chemical, Cargill, Lubrizol and other Fortune 100 companies.

Project Manager Scrum Master (June 2013 – December 2013)

HookLogic, Inc | Ann Arbor, MI

At HookLogic, I was a Scrum Master facilitating Agile Scrum development process including ticket triaging and release QA testing. Some notable accomplishments:

- Developed UI mockups and scope document for a user-tracking system feature
- Cleaned up the sprint backlog of dozens of tickets being carried over from sprint to sprint to provide better visibility into team's performance

Consultant (May 2012 - May 2013) | Business Analyst (September 2010 - May 2012)

Enovio Consulting | Ann Arbor, MI

At Enovio, I worked with a diverse set of clients on projects primarily focused on cost-cutting and change management in energy and education sector. Some notable accomplishments:

- Identified cost cutting initiatives resulting in 10% reduction of corporate operating budget for a utility company and developed a detailed implementation schedule of said initiatives.
- Identified and implemented annual savings of over 25% in resource selection and procurement strategy for a for-profit college without reducing the efficiency of business operations, resulting in over \$600,000 of cost reductions annually.
- Redesigned the internal corporate identity, including firm's logo, brochures and the website.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, School of Information, Ann Arbor, MI MS Information Science with Concentration in Information Economics

May 2012

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI Dual BA in Economics and Sociology

OTHER NOTABLE ACHIEVEMENTS

May 2010

- Fluent in Russian.
- Competes in triathlons, marathons and adventure races.